Richie Chan

+1 437-988-5304 • tfchanag1997@outlook.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/richie-chan-tfchan/ • https://tfchanag.github.io/

About Me

An experienced Mechanical Designer with 2 years of experience in mechanical design for buildings. Skilled in plumbing design, Revit BIM MEP and AutoCAD 2D drafting. I am passionate to contribute my knowledge to improve comfort by designing sustainable and cost-efficient systems, preserving and revitalising historical buildings by adding modernized MEP systems to heritage buildings. My goal is to further develop my skills and knowledge and transition to a professional engineering role.

Skills

Building Service (Plumbing, HVAC) | AutoCAD (Autodesk Certificate) | Revit MEP BIM (Autodesk Certificate) | Excel (VBA) | MEP Equipment Space Coordination | Multi-disciplinary Design Coordination |

Professional Experience

Mar 2020 - May 2021

Assistant Mechanical Engineer - Aurecon, Hong Kong

- Excelled at technical communication by regularly attending design meetings 2 times a week with clients and presenting technical designs clearly and concisely.
- Consistently designed plumbing and drainage systems using AutoCAD and reviewed vendor drawings, ensuring conformity with all regulations and best practices.
- Utilizing problem-solving and analytical skills to revise a drainage design rejected by the government, by studying existing plans, and survey reports. The revised drainage plan gained approval in 2 months.
- Utilizing analytical and quantitative skills to produce design calculations and design briefs for mechanical systems, including sustainable plumbing systems, gained approval from clients.
- As project coordinator, representing MEP consultant and collaborating in a team-based environment with the architect, structural, and environmental engineers, ensuring mechanical systems can be approved by authorities.
- Managed and delivered 3 concurrent projects (2 residential and 1 entertainment), utilizing exceptional multitasking and time management skills to meet deadlines.

July 2019 - Mar 2020

Assistant Building Service Engineer - Hip Hing Construction Company Limited, Hong Kong

- Coordinated on-site activities in a team-based environment, working with sub-contractors and consultants to ensure the mechanical systems were feasible to maintain and construct.
- Maintained accurate and detailed documentation of installation progress, inspection results, testing records, and as-built drawing updates, ensuring compliance with all regulations and requirements.

Education

2015-2019

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

Key courses: Thermodynamics, Fluid Mechanics, Heat Transfer, Electrical Technology

Check out projects I worked on: https://tfchanag.github.io/#/mechanical_projects